<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Reiki Exercises</string>

    <string name="_5_dias_de_inicia_ao">Initiation</string>
    <string name="_7_dias_de_caminho">The Path</string>
    <string name="_5_dias_de_aten_ao_plena">Attention</string>
    <string name="o_caminho_interior">Inner Path</string>
    <string name="eleva_ao_de_consciencia">Consciousness</string>
    <string name="infocincodiasiniciacao">JUST FOR TODAY \n \n Before you start the five days, there is a phrase that deserves attention and reflection. In the precepts, Master Usui says «Just for today». This just for today does not mean that you will just do it on this day and forget about the next. Just for today means the practice of mindfulness - just for today, here and now, in mind and heart. When you start each of these days try to stay in the present moment, savoring each lesson, what you feel, what you think, and you will see that it makes all the difference. \n \n \n HOW TO PERFORM THE FIVE DAYS \n \n It is very simple: try to collect yourself in a quiet space, if you want, put on some serene music, sit down or lie down comfortably, preferably with your back straight. At the beginning of each day you have a poem by Emperor Meiji, which can help you to reflect. Meditate a little on what the beginning of the day tells you and what you would like to see transformed in you. How do you think Reiki can help you achieve that goal? \n \n Also pay attention to your nutrition and hydration. Over these five days, try to eat a more balanced diet. Don\'t overeat red meats, sugar, alcohol and stimulants like coffee, green tea and tobacco. However, you must not leave something that can create anxiety. A balanced diet will only serve to prepare your body for attunement. The less toxins you have, the better. However, nothing impedes your course. Hydration is also very important, even to help the body get rid of toxins. If you can, drink 1.5 l of water a day, unless you feel bad about drinking so much. Taking care with food and hydration, you will have a more harmonized body and a higher energy frequency.</string>
    <string name="cincodiasparacomecarreikititulo">FIVE DAYS TO START PRACTICING REIKI</string>
    <string name="dia_1_s_por_hoje_sou_calmo">DAY 1 - JUST FOR TODAY, I\'M CALM</string>
    <string name="dia_2_s_por_hoje_confio">DAY 2 - JUST FOR TODAY, I TRUST</string>
    <string name="dia_3_s_por_hoje_sou_grato">DAY 3 - JUST FOR TODAY, I AM GRATEFUL</string>
    <string name="dia_4_s_por_hoje_trabalho_honestamente">DAY 4 - JUST FOR TODAY, I WORK HONESTLY</string>
    <string name="dia_5_s_por_hoje_sou_bondoso">DAY 5 - JUST FOR TODAY, I\'M KINDNESS</string>
    <string name="a_gua_que_pena_apesar_de_a_fonte_ser_pura_e_clara_a_gua_torna_se_suja_quando_flui_por_um_riacho_polufdo_imperador_meiji">«The water - What a pity, even though the source is pure and clear, the water becomes dirty when it flows through a polluted stream.» \n - Emperor Meiji</string>
    <string name="reflex_o">REFLECTION</string>
    <string name="como_s_perante_a_vida_e_perante_os_desafios_que_te_surgem_n_n_como_queres_ou_achas_que_o_reiki_pode_ajudar_te_com_as_tuas_quest_es">-> How are you before life and facing the challenges that arise? \n \n-> How do you want or do you think Reiki can help you with your questions?</string>
    <string name="escreve_a_observa_ao">Write an observation</string>
    <string name="o_que_podes_fazer">WHAT YOU CAN DO</string>
    <string name="observa_que_situa_es_que_te_fazem_perder_a_calma_consegues_perceber_que_rea_es_tem_o_teu_corpo_quando_perdes_a_calma_ou_quando_v_s_algu_m_a_perder_a_calma">Observe situations that make you lose your mood. Can you understand what reactions your body has when you lose your mood or when you see someone losing their mood?</string>
    <string name="gravar">Save</string>
    <string name="image">image</string>
    <string name="cincodias_iniciacao">5 Days to start Reiki</string>
    <string name="setedias_caminho">7 Days of Path</string>
    <string name="cincodias_atencaoplena">5 Days of Full Attention</string>
    <string name="vinteumdias_caminhointerior">The Inner Path in 21 Days</string>
    <string name="cincodias_elevacaoconsciencia">5 Days to raise awareness</string>
    <string name="reminisc_ncia_liderando_o_pais_para_que_seja_visto_como_bom_fa_o_o_meu_melhor_usando_as_minhas_faculdades_ao_m_ximo_n_imperador_meiji">«Reminiscence - Leading the country to be seen as good, I do my best using my faculties to the fullest.» \n- Emperor Meiji</string>
    <string name="tens_confian_a_em_t_mesmo_consegues_confiar_nos_outros_n_n_achas_que_consegues_dar_o_teu_melhor_e_sentes_te_reconhecido_por_isso_ou_sentes_necessidade_de_ser_reconhecido_por_isso"><![CDATA[-> Do you have confidence in yourself? Can you trust others? \n \n-> Do you think you can do your best and feel recognized for that, or do you feel the need to be recognized for that?]]></string>
    <string name="o_que_achas_que_a_vida_tem_reservado_para_ti_sentes_te_confiante_do_teu_papel_na_vida_e_do_que_podes_fazer_por_ti_mesmo_e_pelos_outros">What do you think life has in store for you? Do you feel confident about your role in life and what you can do for yourself and for others?</string>
    <string name="jornal_tanta_gente_l_o_jornal_por_conseguinte_dever_se_ia_escrever_sobre_o_que_significativo_em_vez_do_mundano_n_imperador_meiji">«Newspaper - So many people read the newspaper, therefore one should write about what is significant, instead of the mundane.» \n-Emperor Meiji</string>
    <string name="a_gratid_o_significativa_para_ti_de_que_maneira_a_expressas_n_n_o_que_achas_que_preciso_para_haver_mais_gratid_o_no_mundo"><![CDATA[-> Is gratitude meaningful to you? How do you express it? \n\n-> What do you think it takes to have more gratitude in the world?]]></string>
    <string name="a_gratid_o_traz_nos_uma_liberdade_incr_vel_e_uma_grande_capacidade_de_desapego_e_de_entendimento_sobre_as_coisas_hoje_tenta_fazer_o_seguinte_exerc_cio_n_agradece_algo_de_bom_que_te_tenha_acontecido_n_agradece_algo_de_mau_que_te_tenha_acontecido_n_como_te_sentiste">Gratitude brings us incredible freedom and a great capacity for detachment and understanding about things. Today, try to do the following exercise: \n* Appreciate something good that happened to you; \n* Appreciate something bad that happened to you. \nHow did you feel?</string>
    <string name="pr_tica_a_menos_que_o_teu_trabalho_aponte_para_o_bem_estar_geral_muito_dif_cil_conduzir_os_povos_neste_mundo_n_imperador_meiji">«Practice - Unless your work is aimed at general well-being, it is very difficult to lead people in this world.» \n-Emperor Meiji</string>
    <string name="a_honestidade_importante_para_ti_n_n_s_honesto_contigo_mesmo"><![CDATA[-> Is honesty important to you? \n\n-> Are you honest with yourself?]]></string>
    <string name="como_costumas_encarar_a_honestidade_achas_que_algo_importante_os_outros_terem_contigo_e_tu_com_eles_ndesenvolves_essa_honestidade_contigo_mesmo_nhoje_experimenta_falar_contigo_mesmo_primeiro_coisas_simples_como_uma_conversa_de_amigos_ndepois_experimenta_falar_contigo_sobre_as_coisas_que_te_preocupam_n_como_te_sentes_nessa_intimidade_contigo_mesmo">How do you usually view honesty? Do you think it is important for others to have you and you with them? \nDo you develop that honesty with yourself? \nToday, try talking to yourself. First simple things, like a conversation with friends; \nThen try talking to you about the things that worry you. \n How do you feel in that intimacy with yourself?</string>
    <string name="como_esperas_que_os_outros_sejam_bondosos_para_ti_n_nde_que_forma_achas_que_o_reiki_te_ajudar_com_a_bondade">How do you expect others to be kind to you? \n\nHow do you think Reiki will help you with kindness?</string>
    <string name="neste_dia_observa_te_na_qualidade_de_pessoa_bondosa_como_recebes_os_gestos_dos_outros_mesmo_que_n_o_sejam_bondosos_e_como_tu_s_bondoso_para_com_os_outr_s_nexperimenta_observar_o_que_te_rodeia_quando_est_s_a_caminho_do_trabalho_ou_de_casa_de_que_forma_te_faz_sentido_a_vida_e_o_espa_o_que_ela_ocupa_em_ti">On this day, observe yourself as a kind person. How you receive the gestures of others, even if they are not kind, and how kind you are to others. \nTry to observe what surrounds you when you are on the way to work or home, in what way life and life make sense to you. space that it occupies in you.</string>
    <string name="muitoobrigadoporcuidaresdeti">THANK YOU SO MUCH BY CARING FOR YOU</string>
    <string name="muitoobrigadopelos5dias">Thank you very much for your five-day process. I hope it was very positive for you and aroused your taste for transformation. With a Level 1 course, you will see how you can make this transformation consistently. \n \nMaster Usui used to say that Reiki is the secret art of inviting happiness with good reason. Reiki calls for work, constancy and above all experience. This is what helps us to be happy and to do better and better. \nThese five days were just an introduction to the reflection and goals you may want to achieve with your Reiki practice. When you start to work with energy, you will also be able to work on the issues you observed. \nDon\'t be in a hurry, it\'s like building a house: \n \nTake the time and, the more love you take each step, the more solid your construction, without limits, it will remain. \n \nJust for today, I am grateful.</string>
    <string name="dia_1_muladhara">Day 1 - MULADHARA</string>
    <string name="dia_2_svadhisthana">Day 2 - SVADHISTHANA</string>
    <string name="dia_3_manipura">Day 3 – MANIPURA</string>
    <string name="dia_4_anahata">Day 4 - ANAHATA</string>
    <string name="dia_5_vishuddha">Day 5 - VISHUDDHA</string>
    <string name="dia_6_ajna">Day 6 - AJNA</string>
    <string name="dia_7_sahasrara">Day 7 - SAHASRARA</string>
    <string name="o_nosso_corpo_tem_uma_sabedoria_n_s_desconhecemos_damos_lhe_ordens_que_n_o_fazem_sentido_algum_n_henry_miller_n_n_nhoje_iniciamos_o_primeiro_dia_do_nosso_caminho_uma_viagem_conjunta_mas_de_viv_ncia_muito_pessoal_e_interior_e_assim_mesmo_a_vida_quando_caminhamos_mais_despertos_trabalhamos_o_interior_para_podermos_dar_mais_para_o_exterior_desejo_te_um_caminho_muito_bonito_e_cheio_de_alegria_n_n_n_o_sigas_o_passado_n_o_te_percas_no_futuro_o_passado_j_n_o_existe_o_futuro_ainda_n_o_chegou_observando_profundamente_a_vida_como_ela_aqui_e_agora_permanecemos_equilibrados_e_livres_n_koan_zen_n_nneste_primeiro_dia_no_caminho_vais_trabalhar_o_estar_no_aquie_agora_a_consci_ncia_da_tua_raiz_e_a_import_ncia_do_presente_n_o_te_apegues_ao_que_se_passou_nem_desejes_tanto_o_que_vai_acontecer_s_consegues_ser_feliz_agora_nse_puderes_arranja_um_caderno_para_colocares_as_quest_es_e_as_tuas_reflex_es_ir_ajudar_te_a_compreenderes_o_conjunto_de_todo_este_trabalho_e_a_perceberes_no_futuro_como_cresceste_n_n_como_te_sentes_neste_momento_n_achas_que_est_s_muito_agarrado_ao_passado_ou_a_querer_viver_o_futuro_n_como_te_encontras_com_a_vida_aqui_e_agora_sentes_te_feliz_n_o_que_achas_que_te_impede_de_ser_feliz_neste_exato_momento_n_o_que_vais_fazer_para_te_tornares_feliz_em_cada_momento_no_presente_n_n_na_tua_raiz_o_que_te_liga_terra_s_pessoas_e_a_constru_o_da_tua_tribo_e_do_teu_poder_neste_momento_e_a_tua_afirma_o_e_concretiza_o_e_a_sobreviv_ncia_enquanto_ser_com_a_cor_vermelha_n_o_tens_medo_e_tens_for_a_a_vibra_o_mais_baixa_de_todos_os_chacras_mas_a_que_d_resistencia_ao_teu_corpo_que_um_templo_sagrado_como_te_d_s_com_o_chacra_da_raiz_sentes_te_no_aqui_e_agora_enraizas_te_sentes_te_integrado_consegues_usar_o_vermelho">«Our body has a wisdom we don\'t know. We give you orders that make no sense at all. »\n-Henry Miller\n\n\nToday we start the first day of our journey. A joint trip but with a very personal and inner experience. And so is life, when we walk more awake. We work on the inside so that we can give more to the outside. I wish you a very beautiful and joyful path.\n\n«Do not follow the past; don\'t get lost in the future. The past no longer exists, the future has not yet arrived. Deeply observing life as it is, here and now, we remain balanced and free. »\n-Koan Zen\n\nIn this first day on the way, you will work on being here, the awareness of your root and the importance of the present. Do not cling to what happened, nor long for what will happen. You can only be happy now.\nIf you can, get yourself a notebook to ask questions and your thoughts. It will help you to understand the whole of this work and to understand in the future how you grew up.\n\n* How do you feel at the moment?\n* Do you think you are too attached to the past or wanting to live the future?\n* How do you find life, here and now? Do you feel happy?\n* What do you think keeps you from being happy right now?\n* What are you going to do to make yourself happy in every moment, in the present?\n\n\nYour root is what connects you to the land, to people. And building your tribe and your power, right now. And your affirmation and concretization. And survival as a being. With the red color you are not afraid and you have strength. It is the lowest vibration of all chakras, but it is the one that gives resistance to your body, which is a sacred temple. How do you get on with the Root Chakra? Do you feel in the here and now? Are you rooted? Do you feel integrated? Can you use red?</string>
    <string name="pr_ticas">PRACTICES</string>
    <string name="neste_primeiro_dia_guarda_um_momento_para_tomares_consci_ncia_de_ti_mesmo_sente_os_teus_pes_no_ch_o_eo_ar_que_inspiras_toma_consci_ncia_de_cada_momento_nico_de_vida_s_por_hoje_como_o_enraizamento_importante_dedica_te_a_esta_pr_tica_v_rias_vezes_por_dia_se_te_desenraizares_com_frequ_ncia_n_o_te_preocupes_normal_e_o_teu_corpo_energ_tico_vai_aprendendo_a_enraizar_se_ao_longo_do_dia_vai_tendo_consci_ncia_do_momento_presente_sente_o_ar_o_que_v_s_o_que_tocas_o_que_saboreias">On this first day, take a moment to become aware of yourself. Feel your feet on the floor and the air you breathe, Be aware of every single moment of life… Just for today. As rooting is important, dedicate yourself to this practice several times a day. If you uproot yourself frequently, don\'t worry, it\'s normal and your energetic body learns to take root. Throughout the day you become aware of the present moment… Feel the air, what you see, what you touch, what you taste.</string>
    <string name="t_cnicas_de_reiki">REIKI TECHNIQUES</string>
    <string name="fechar">Close</string>
    <string name="como_hoje_trabalhamos_o_aqui_e_agora_a_melhor_forma_de_o_fazer_atrav_s_da_medita_o_gassho_n_ncome_a_da_seguinte_forma_n_n1_liga_te_energia_reiki_n2_deixa_fluir_para_a_mente_e_para_o_cora_o_n3_recita_os_cinco_princ_pios_n4_observa_como_est_s_sente_te_n5_pratica_o_enraizamento_o_banho_seco_e_a_chuva_de_reiki_n6_observa_como_est_s_novamente_n7_senta_te_confortavelmente_e_coloca_as_m_os_em_gassho_junto_n8_recita_os_cinco_princ_pios_lentamente_e_sente_a_vibra_o_de_cada_um_no_teu_corpo_e_a_aura_n9_concentra_te_apenas_na_respira_o_e_imagina_que_inspiras_reiki_n_o_s_pelo_chacra_da_coroa_e_pelo_nariz_como_tamb_m_pelos_dedos_m_dios_n10_se_te_concentrares_na_entrada_de_energia_pelo_dedo_m_dio_ter_s_mais_serenidade_e_verificar_s_como_a_energia_entra_em_ti_n11_se_puderes_efetua_este_exerc_cio_durante_10_minutos_n12_no_final_agradece">As we work here and now, the best way to do it is through Gassho meditation. \n\nStart as follows: \n\n1- Connect to Reiki energy; \n2- Let it flow into your mind and into the heart; \n3- Recite the Five Principles; \n4- Observe how you are, feel yourself; \n5- Practice rooting, dry bath and Reiki rain; \n6- Observe how you are, again; \n7- Sit comfortably and place your hands on Gassho together \n8- Recite the Five Principles slowly and feel the vibration of each one in your body and the aura; \n9- Focus only on your breath and imagine that you inspire Reiki not only by Crown Chakra and the nose as well as the middle fingers; \n10- If you focus on the energy input through the middle finger, you will have more serenity and see how the energy enters you; \n11- If you can, do this exercise for 10 minutes : \n12- In the end, thank you.</string>
    <string name="muitas_vezes_as_m_os_ir_o_resolver_um_mist_rio_com_que_o_intelecto_tem_lutado_em_v_o_carl_g_jung_n_nneste_segundo_dia_de_reflex_o_e_trabalho_interior_vamos_dedicar_nos_ao_nosso_segundo_chacra_observar_os_objetivos_de_vida_a_nossa_liberdade_e_a_presen_a_no_mundo_observa_as_seguintes_quest_es_e_tenta_perceber_como_tens_estado_perante_ti_mesmo_e_ante_os_que_te_rodeiam_n_n_praticas_os_cinco_princ_pios_e_consegues_senti_los_em_ti_fazem_parte_do_teu_quotidiano_e_sentes_a_transforma_o_que_eles_te_trazem_n_consegues_aplicar_o_segundo_princ_pio_s_por_hoje_sou_calmo_nas_situa_es_mais_dif_ceis_se_n_o_o_que_achas_que_te_podia_ajudar_a_conseguir_o_que_vais_fazer_para_seres_mais_equilibrado_nas_tuas_decis_es_n_qual_o_teu_maior_objetivo_de_vida_neste_momento_est_s_com_for_a_para_o_realizar_se_n_o_como_achas_que_vais_conseguir_e_de_que_forma_o_reiki_poder_ajudar_n_no_chacra_espl_nico_trabalha_com_os_objetivos_de_vida_a_liberdade_a_alegria_a_criatividade_a_sexualidade_a_rela_o_intima_com_o_outro_os_rg_os_sexuais_verifica_estas_situa_es_em_ti_n_n_como_te_relacionas_com_os_outros_sentes_te_uma_pessoa_envolvente_e_carism_tica_n_tens_objetivos_de_vida_n_sentes_te_uma_pessoa_livre_ou_constrangida_porque_n_n_quando_admiro_a_maravilha_de_um_p_r_do_sol_ou_a_beleza_da_lua_a_minha_alma_expande_se_em_rever_ncia_ao_criador_mahatma_gandhi">«Often, the hands will solve a mystery that the intellect has struggled with in vain.» - Carl G. Jung\n\nIn this second day of reflection and inner work, we will dedicate ourselves to our second chakra - to observe the goals of life, our freedom and our presence in the world. Observe the following questions and try to understand how you have been before yourself and before those around you:\n\n* Do you practice the Five Principles and can you feel them in you? Are they part of your daily life and do you feel the transformation they bring you?\n* Can you apply the second principle, just for today, am I calm, in the most difficult situations? If not, what do you think could help you achieve? What are you going to do to be more balanced in your decisions?\n* What is your biggest life goal right now? Are you strong enough to do it? If not, how do you think you will achieve it and how can Reiki help?\n\nThe Splenic Chakra works with life goals, freedom, joy, creativity, sexuality, the intimate relationship with the other, the sexual organs. Check these situations in you:\n\n* How do you relate to others? Do you feel an engaging and charismatic person?\n* Do you have life goals?\n* Do you feel free or embarrassed? Why?\n\n«When I admire the wonder of a sunset or the beauty of the Moon, my soul expands in reverence to the Creator.» - Mahatma Gandhi</string>
    <string name="para_trabalhares_o_chacra_espl_nico_tens_de_fazer_atividades_que_te_tragam_realiza_o_exerc_cio_fisico_brincar_rir_apanhar_sol_e_coisas_que_te_disponham_interiormente_que_te_fa_am_sentir_vivo">To work the Chacra Esplénico you have to do activities that bring you fulfillment: physical exercise, playing, laughing, sunbathing and things that make you feel inside, that make you feel alive.</string>
    <string name="ao_fazeres_o_teu_autotratamento_coloca_a_inten_o_de_te_preencher_de_vitalidade_e_alegria_a_alegria_muito_importante_para_o_chacra_espl_nico_n_purifica_as_tuas_emo_es_com_o_hesso_chiryo_que_uma_t_cnica_muito_vital_para_a_desintoxica_o_n_pratica_o_banho_seco_e_a_chuva_de_reiki_para_eliminares_algo_que_tenha_ficado_na_tua_aura_com_a_limpeza">* When doing your self-treatment, place the intention to fill yourself with vitality and joy. Joy is very important for the Splenic Chakra;\n* Purify your emotions with Hesso Chiryo, which is a very vital technique for detoxification;\n* Practice the dry bath and the Reiki rain, to eliminate something that was left in your aura with the cleaning.</string>
    <string name="qual_era_o_teu_rosto_original_aquele_que_possu_as_antes_de_nascer_koan_zen_n_nhoje_ir_s_ao_encontro_do_teu_poder_pessoal_para_o_consolidar_torna_esse_teu_poder_numa_for_a_para_ajudar_os_outros_e_a_ti_mesmo_ns_por_hoje_sou_grato_de_que_s_grato_no_koan_zen_remete_para_a_reflex_o_de_quem_sou_eu_verdadeiramente_esta_procura_pelo_eu_pela_verdadeira_identidade_torna_se_num_caminho_mais_sereno_quando_preenchido_pela_gratid_o_agrade_o_por_tudo_o_que_sou_incluindo_as_partes_que_s_o_m_s_poderia_dizer_menos_boas_mas_n_o_precisamos_de_identificar_claramente_aquilo_que_muitas_vezes_escondemos_e_luz_da_gratid_o_unir_nos_num_todo_tu_s_um_todo_pleno_das_coisas_que_s_o_m_s_e_boas_e_o_resultado_dessa_uni_o_o_ser_incr_vel_que_tu_manifestas_a_dentro_est_uma_luz_extraordin_ria_s_tu_neste_dia_do_caminho_sente_te_sente_o_teu_poder_interior_rev_estas_quest_es_n_n_sei_reconhecer_os_meus_limites_se_n_o_o_que_preciso_para_me_conhecer_melhor_n_sei_agradecer_por_todas_as_li_es_que_eu_mesmo_me_atribuo_na_vida_n_sei_usar_o_meu_poder_pessoal_para_me_construir_e_ajudar_os_outros_a_constru_rem_se_se_n_o_o_que_preciso_para_o_fazer_n_no_chacra_do_plexo_solar_manipura_n_no_plexo_solar_a_fonte_do_nosso_poder_pessoal_visualiza_o_como_um_sol_e_compreender_s_que_a_que_reside_a_tua_for_a_interior_direita_tem_o_figado_e_esquerda_o_ba_o_a_depura_o_e_os_pensamentos_o_plexo_solar_tamb_m_chamado_chacra_simp_tico_porque_se_lembra_de_absorver_a_energia_dissonante_que_o_rodeia_provocando_incha_o_na_barriga_sensa_o_extrema_de_acumula_o_e_mal_estar_tudo_porque_n_o_est_capaz_de_processar_e_de_transformar_a_energia_que_absorveu_este_o_chacra_pelo_qual_comunicamos_as_nossas_emo_es_basta_reparar_que_cruzamos_os_bra_os_frente_ao_plexo_solar_quando_queremos_fechar_nos_para_os_outros_nesta_base_de_poder_reflete_tamb_m_no_seguinte_n_n_sei_lidar_com_as_minhas_emo_es_n_conhe_o_me_na_totalidade_e_identifico_o_que_preciso_n_sou_dependente_de_alguma_forma_n_tenho_problemas_na_zona_da_barriga">«What was your original face, the one you had before you were born?» - Koan Zen\n\nToday you will find your personal power to consolidate it. Make that power of yours a force to help others and yourself.\nJust for today, I\'m grateful … What are you grateful for? Koan Zen refers to the reflection of “who am I really?”. This search for self, for true identity, becomes a more serene path when it is filled with gratitude - I thank you for all that I am, including the parts that are bad. I could say "less good" but no, we need to clearly identify what we often hide and, in the light of gratitude, unite as a whole. You are a whole, full of the things that are bad and good, and the result of that union is the incredible being that you manifest. Inside there is an extraordinary light - it\'s you.\nOn this day on the way, sit down. Feel your inner power! Review these questions:\n\n* Do I know my limits? If not, what do I need to know me better?\n* Do I know how to thank you for all the lessons I attribute to myself in life?\n* Do I know how to use my personal power to build myself and help others to build themselves? If not, what do you need to do?\n\nTHE CHACRA OF THE SOLAR PLEXUS - MANIPURA\n\nThe Solar Plexus is the source of our personal power. Visualize it as a sun and you will understand that this is where your inner strength resides. On the right there is the liver and on the left the spleen - the purification and thoughts. The Solar Plexus is also called Sympathetic Chakra, because it remembers to absorb the dissonant energy that surrounds it, causing swelling in the belly, extreme feeling of accumulation and malaise, all because it is not able to process and transform the energy it has absorbed. This is the chakra by which we communicate our emotions; just notice that we fold our arms in front of the Solar Plexus when we want to close ourselves off from others. On this basis of power, it also reflects the following:\n\n* Do I know how to deal with my emotions?\n* Do I know myself fully and identify what I need?\n* Am I dependent in any way?\n* Do I have problems in the belly area?</string>
    <string name="o_teu_trabalho_com_o_plexo_solar_passa_por_compreenderes_e_aceitares_o_teu_poder_pessoal_imagina_um_grande_sol_forte_e_incrivelmente_quente_coloca_o_no_teu_chacra_do_plexo_solar_como_te_sentes">Your work with the Solar Plexus involves understanding and accepting your personal power. Imagine a big sun, strong and incredibly hot - place it on your Solar Plexus Chakra. How do you feel?</string>
    <string name="depois_do_teu_autotratamento_coloca_uma_m_o_no_plexo_solar_e_outra_no_chacra_card_aco_pois_vai_ajudar_te_a_harmonizar_as_emo_es_com_o_amor_incondicional_deixa_te_estar_assim_por_algum_tempo_n_ao_longo_do_dia_tenta_colocar_assim_as_maos_em_momentos_de_repouso_sentes_te_bem">* After your self-treatment, put one hand on the Solar Plexus and the other on the Heart Chakra, as it will help you to harmonize emotions with unconditional love. Let yourself be like this for a while;\n* Throughout the day try to put your hands like this, in moments of rest. Do you feel well?</string>
    <string name="o_reiki_a_arte_secreta_de_convidar_a_felicidade_mikao_usui_n_nno_n_mero_quatro_encontras_a_estabilidade_os_quatro_lados_o_quadrado_o_quarto_chacra_o_card_aco_o_amor_incondicional_ressoa_com_o_reiki_e_com_o_quarto_chacra_sente_o_s_por_hoje_trabalho_honestamente_trabalho_a_verdade_e_partilho_em_verdade_assim_o_quarto_princ_pio_do_reiki_que_coincide_com_o_quarto_chacra_o_card_aco_quando_o_cora_o_bate_e_trabalha_tudo_funciona_e_o_mundo_interior_cresce_em_beleza_e_transborda_para_o_exterior_o_cora_o_pede_simplicidade_e_preenchimento_este_n_o_pode_ser_exterior_mas_interior_eu_sou_pleno_em_mim_consegues_sentir_desta_forma_n_n_sentes_te_preenchido_totalmente_se_n_o_o_que_achas_que_falta_e_de_que_maneira_o_poder_s_preencher_n_o_que_te_pede_o_cora_o_neste_preciso_momento_se_escutas_consegues_cumprir_o_que_ele_precisa_n_no_quarto_chacra_tamb_m_chamado_inviol_vel_este_tesouro_que_temos_no_peito_o_amor_incondicional_o_jardim_da_nossa_compaix_o_e_inestim_vel_e_a_fonte_inesgot_vel_do_que_h_de_mais_precioso_0_amor_nquando_temos_o_cora_o_predisposto_tudo_flui_n_o_interessa_quem_esta_a_frente_flui_a_energia_cumpre_o_seu_prop_sito_e_n_s_sentimo_nos_realizados_o_chacra_card_aco_o_motor_do_reiki_e_da_evolu_o_da_nossa_consci_ncia_escuta_o_que_ele_tem_para_te_dizer_n_n_costumas_escutar_o_teu_cora_o_o_que_te_diz_com_frequ_ncia_n_achas_que_tens_mais_para_dar_do_que_para_receber_porque_n_sabes_receber_de_certeza">«Reiki is the secret art of inviting happiness.» - Mikao Usui\n\nIn number four you find stability: the four sides, the square, the fourth chakra - the Heart. Unconditional love resonates with Reiki and the fourth chakra. Sit it down. Just for today, I work honestly - I work the truth and I share in truth. So is the fourth principle of Reiki, which coincides with the fourth heart chakra. When the heart beats and works, everything works and the inner world grows in beauty and overflows to the outside. The heart asks for simplicity and fulfillment. This cannot be exterior but interior. I am, full of me. Can you feel this way?\n\n* Do you feel full? Totally? If not, what do you think is missing and how can you fill it out?\n* What does the heart ask of you right now? If you listen, can you fulfill what he needs?\n\nThe fourth chakra is also called "inviolable". This treasure that we have in our hearts, unconditional love, the garden of our compassion, is priceless and is the inexhaustible source of what is most precious - love.\nWhen we have a predisposed heart everything flows - it doesn\'t matter who is ahead, it flows. Energy fulfills its purpose and we feel fulfilled. The Heart Chakra is the engine of Reiki and the evolution of our consciousness - listen to what it has to say to you.\n\n* Do you ever listen to your heart? What do you say often?\n* Do you think you have more to give than to receive? Why?\n* Do you know how to receive? Are you sure?</string>
    <string name="coloca_as_m_os_no_chacra_card_aco_na_regi_o_do_timo_e_deixa_fluir_reiki_sente_o_calor_agrad_vel_da_energia_a_preencher_o_teu_peito_e_a_fazer_com_que_o_teu_jardim_interior_cres_a_e_fique_brilhante_sorri_interiormente">Put your hands on the Heart Chakra, in the thymus region, and let Reiki flow. Feel the pleasant warmth of energy filling your chest and making your inner garden grow and shine. I smiled inwardly.</string>
    <string name="depois_do_autotratamento_pratica_o_nentatsu_esvazia_a_mente_coloca_a_virtude_que_queres_alcan_ar_e_deixa_fluir_o_reiki_para_que_essa_virtude_cres_a_como_te_sentes">* After self-treatment, practice Nentatsu. Empty the mind, put the virtue you want to achieve and let Reiki flow, so that that virtue grows. How do you feel?</string>
    <string name="nada_te_posso_dar_a_n_o_ser_a_oportunidade_o_impulso_a_chave_eu_ajudarei_a_tornar_vis_vel_o_teu_pr_prio_mundo_e_isso_tudo_hermann_hesse_n_ncomunicar_preciso_mas_quando_faz_lo_e_como_o_fazer_ns_por_hoje_sou_bondoso_o_que_te_diz_esta_bondade_n_n_que_bondade_tens_para_contigo_n_que_bondade_tens_para_com_os_outros_n_achas_te_mais_bondoso_para_contigo_do_que_para_os_outros_porqu_n_nneste_processo_de_trabalhar_a_bondade_n_o_precisamos_de_muitas_palavras_mas_de_sentir_corretamente_os_dois_cora_es_a_trabalharem_mente_e_cora_o_sentes_essa_harmonia_e_a_plena_comunica_o_n_no_chacra_lar_ngeo_a_porta_o_canal_entre_esses_dois_cora_es_como_est_essa_tua_porta_no_quinto_chacra_o_da_comunica_o_que_tamb_m_tem_a_ver_com_a_bondade_do_quinto_princ_pio_e_o_chacra_da_express_o_do_di_logo_interior_e_exterior_do_comum_e_do_extrassensorial_comunicar_preciso_e_de_todas_as_formas_com_bondade_a_lua_representada_no_vishuddha_a_nossa_parte_ps_quica_e_oculta_assim_a_comunica_o_tem_algo_de_extraordin_rio_de_al_m_mat_ria_a_comunica_o_com_o_universo_e_com_a_vida_reflete_sobre_as_seguintes_quest_es_n_n_sabes_comunicar_contigo_e_com_os_outros_n_escutas_a_sabedoria_da_vida_e_sabes_comunic_la_aos_outros_n_ouves_o_que_o_universo_tem_para_ti_compreendes_verdadeiramente_a_dimens_o_espiritual">«I can give you nothing but the opportunity, the momentum, the key. I will help to make your own world visible, and that is all. » - Hermann Hesse\n\nCommunicating is necessary, but when to do it, and how to do it?\nJust for today, I\'m kind. What does this kindness tell you?\n\n* What kindness do you have for you?\n* What kindness do you have towards others?\n* Do you think you are kinder to yourself than to others? Why?\n\nIn this process of working on kindness, we don\'t need many words but to feel the two hearts at work correctly - mind and heart. Do you feel that harmony and full communication?\n\nThe Throat Chakra is the door, the channel between these two hearts. How\'s your door?\nThe fifth chakra is that of communication, which also has to do with the goodness of the fifth principle. It is the chakra of expression, of inner and outer dialogue, of the common and the extrasensory. Communicating is accurate and all forms … with kindness. The Moon, represented in Vishuddha, is our psychic and hidden part; thus, communication has something extraordinary, beyond matter is communication with the Universe and with life. Reflects on the following issues:\n\n* Can you communicate with you? And with others?\n* Do you listen to the wisdom of life and know how to communicate it to others?\n* Do you hear what the Universe has for you? Do you really understand the spiritual dimension?</string>
    <string name="tratar_o_chacra_lar_ngeo_nem_sempre_confort_vel_como_p_r_as_m_os_relaxa_coloca_uma_m_o_perto_da_base_do_pesco_o_em_contacto_com_a_tiroide_e_a_outra_mais_abaixo_em_contacto_com_o_timo_assim_est_s_a_trabalhar_a_comunica_o_com_o_amor_incondicional_o_quinto_chacra_com_o_quinto_princ_pio_0_que_sentes_nn_o_te_esque_as_de_colocar_a_inten_o_a_bondade_para_contigo_mesmo_a_harmonia_o_amor">Treating the Throat Chakra is not always comfortable … How to put hands? Relax. Place one hand near the base of the neck, in contact with the thyroid, and the other lower, in contact with the thymus. So you are working on communication with unconditional love, the fifth chakra with the fifth principle. What do you feel?\nDo not forget to put the intention - kindness (for yourself), harmony, love.</string>
    <string name="faz_medita_o_gassho_e_recita_audivelmente_os_cinco_princ_pios_do_reiki_f_los_vibrar_atrav_s_do_chacra_card_aco_saiu_mais_forte">Do Gassho meditation and recite the Five Principles of Reiki audibly. It makes them vibrate through the Heart Chakra. Did it come out stronger?</string>
    <string name="exige_muito_de_ti_e_espera_pouco_dos_outros_assim_evitar_s_muitos_aborrecimentos_conf_cio_n_nest_s_no_dia_da_consci_ncia_e_da_vis_o_interior_e_a_nossa_consci_ncia_que_observa_e_que_cresce_com_a_pr_tica_dos_princ_pios_quanto_mais_conscientes_ficamos_mais_felizes_somos_mais_independentes_nos_tornamos_e_compreendemos_o_nosso_papel_no_universo_a_par_com_o_de_todos_os_outros_e_ent_o_temos_de_nos_perguntar_n_n_oue_consci_ncia_tenho_de_mim_sei_quem_sou_n_aceito_o_meu_papel_e_o_papel_dos_outros_na_vida_se_n_o_porqu_n_quero_verdadeiramente_ser_consciente_ou_prefer_vel_por_enquanto_n_o_estar_muito_consciente_n_na_terceira_vis_o_rege_a_tua_intui_o_a_capacidade_de_ir_ao_mais_profundo_de_ti_enquanto_te_ligas_ao_universo_e_v_s_as_coisas_como_elas_s_o_para_l_dos_olhos_fisicos_a_tua_vis_o_interior_ser_t_o_apurada_quanto_a_tua_capacidade_para_manteres_uma_mente_limpa_e_a_consci_ncia_elevada_as_exig_ncias_do_quotidiano_e_os_est_mulos_cada_vez_mais_intensos_e_presentes_na_nossa_vida_impedem_te_muitas_vezes_de_ver_corretamente_nent_o_tens_de_te_perguntar_n_n_consigo_ver_claramente_as_situa_es_e_tomar_as_melhores_decis_es_n_sei_escutar_a_minha_intui_o_acredito_no_que_sinto_e_pressinto_porque_n_de_que_forma_me_conhe_o_como_ser_como_esp_rito_como_parte_para_l_do_corpo">"Requires a lot from you and expect little of others. This way, you will avoid many hassles. » - Confucius\n\nYou are in the day of awareness and inner vision. It is our conscience that observes and grows with the practice of the principles. The more aware we are the happier we are, the more independent we become and we understand our role in the Universe, on a par with everyone else. And then we have to ask ourselves:\n\n* What awareness do I have of myself? Do I know who I am?\n* Do I accept my role and the role of others in life? If not, why not?\n* Do I really want to be conscious, or is it preferable for the time being not very conscious?\n\nThe Third Vision governs your intuition, the ability to go to the depths of you while you connect with the Universe and see things as they are, beyond the physical eyes. Your inner vision will be as sharp as your ability to keep a clear mind and a heightened awareness. The demands of everyday life and the increasingly intense and present stimuli in our life often prevent you from seeing correctly.\nSo you have to ask yourself:\n\n* Can I see the situations clearly and make the best decisions?\n* Do I know how to listen to my intuition? Do I believe what I feel and feel? Why?\n* How do I know myself as a being, as a spirit, as a part beyond the body?</string>
    <string name="tenta_perceber_qual_o_teu_ponto_mais_fraco_que_chacra_que_rg_o_ap_s_o_tratamento_coloca_uma_m_o_na_terceira_vis_o_e_outra_nessa_regi_o_intui_tenta_perceber_o_que_a_energia_te_quer_dizer_sobre_essa_tua_fragilidade_est_s_a_tomar_consci_ncia_de_ti_e_a_tornares_te_forte">Try to understand your weakest point. What a chakra, what an organ. After treatment, put a hand on the Third Vision and another on that region. Intuition, try to understand what the energy wants to tell you about your fragility. You are becoming aware of yourself and becoming strong!</string>
    <string name="pratica_o_hesso_chiryo_para_a_desintoxica_o">Practice Hesso Chiryo, for detoxification.</string>
    <string name="ser_feliz_ter_futuro_e_dar_futuro_vasco_pinto_de_magalh_es_n_nhoje_dia_da_nossa_liga_o_ao_universo_por_isso_fica_atento_s_gue_mensagens_ele_conspira_contigo_e_isso_quer_dizer_que_est_o_em_sintonia_depois_dos_princ_pios_e_da_perce_o_da_consci_ncia_vem_a_nossa_ligac_o_fonte_ao_universo_que_feita_pelo_chacra_da_coroa_a_nossa_felicidade_vem_da_capacidade_de_compreendermos_que_temos_de_ser_completos_ligados_ao_c_u_ligados_terra_tudo_faz_o_seu_sentido_e_a_vida_espera_por_n_s_vale_a_pena_viv_la_se_lhe_tivermos_paix_o_e_amor_o_desapego_esse_fica_para_aquelas_coisas_que_apenas_nos_prejudicam_o_amor_fica_para_a_vida_e_para_tudo_o_que_sentimos_amar_incondicionalmente_n_n_de_que_forma_sentes_que_te_ligas_ao_reiki_o_que_te_traz_n_sentes_a_mesma_coisa_com_a_vida_porqu_n_como_s_feliz_o_que_vais_fazer_para_ser_feliz_n_nsahasrara_o_l_tus_das_mil_p_talas_a_pureza_que_se_liga_ao_universo_atrav_s_deste_chacra_que_alcan_amos_a_supraconsci_ncia_e_a_sensa_o_de_ilumina_o_e_clareza_de_esp_rito_quando_o_chacra_est_aberto_tamb_m_a_nossa_mente_se_encontra_aberta_ao_mundo_das_ideias_reflete_no_seguinte_n_n_consideras_te_uma_pessoa_de_vastos_horizontes_e_mente_aberta_n_o_que_identificas_como_limita_es_do_teu_pensamento_n_que_coisas_arcaicas_fora_do_tempo_ainda_te_restringem_n_sentes_te_um_ser_de_luz_porqu_n_o_que_ir_s_fazer_para_s_lo_cada_vez_mais_n_n_ser_feliz_ter_futuro_e_dar_futuro_todos_pensamos_ser_felizes_e_acordamos_todos_os_dias_com_esse_desejo_mas_ser_feliz_n_o_uma_sorte_nem_a_aus_ncia_de_problemas_e_viver_com_sentido_com_coragem_construindo_o_futuro_e_dando_futuro_isso_depende_de_mim_era_uma_vez_um_homem_que_corria_e_corria_pela_vida_a_vida_era_curta_e_necessitava_de_correr_muito_para_gozar_muito_e_ser_feliz_e_quanto_mais_corria_mais_necessitava_de_correr_descobria_sempre_mais_lugares_para_visitar_necessitava_de_encontrar_tudo_e_gozar_tudo_at_que_um_dia_cansado_de_tanto_correr_parou_ent_o_a_felicidade_p_de_alcan_lo_vasco_pinto_de_magalh_es_n_o_h_solu_es_h_caminhos">«To be happy is to have a future and to give a future.» -Vasco Pinto de Magalhães.\n\nToday is the day of our connection to the Universe, so stay tuned for messages. He conspires with you and that means you are in tune. After the principles and the perception of consciousness comes our connection to the source, to the Universe, which is made by the Crown Chakra. Our happiness comes from the ability to understand that we have to be complete, connected to heaven, connected to earth. Everything makes sense and life awaits us. It is worth living it if we have passion and love for it. Detachment is for those things that only harm us; love remains for life and for everything we feel we love unconditionally.\n\n* How do you feel you connect with Reiki? What brings you?\n* Do you feel the same way about life? Why?\n* How happy are you? What are you going to do to be happy?\n\nSahasrara is the lotus of a thousand petals, the purity that connects to the Universe. It is through this chakra that we reach supraconsciousness and the feeling of enlightenment and clarity of spirit. When the chakra is open, our mind is also open to the world of ideas. It reflects on the following:\n\n* Do you consider yourself a person with wide horizons and an open mind?\n* What do you identify as limitations of your thinking?\n* What archaic things, outside of time, still restrict you?\n* Do you feel a being of light? Why?\n* What will you do to be more and more?\n\n«To be happy is to have a future and to give a future. We all think we are happy and we wake up every day with that desire. But being happy is not luck or the absence of problems. And to live with meaning, with courage, building the future and giving the future. That depends on me. Once upon a time there was a man who ran and ran for his life … Life was short and he needed to run a lot to enjoy a lot and be happy. And the more I ran the more I needed to run …! He always found more places to visit. I needed to find everything and enjoy everything. Until one day, tired of running, he stopped. Then, happiness could reach him. » - Vasco Pinto de Magalhães, There are no Solutions, There are Paths.</string>
    <string name="coloca_as_m_os_no_chacra_da_coroa_tenta_encontrar_a_posi_o_mais_confort_vel_para_que_ele_receba_reiki_imagina_que_a_energia_vai_para_a_glandula_pineal_e_que_te_preenche_com_harmonia_e_felicidade">Put your hands on the Crown Chakra. Try to find the most comfortable position for him to receive Reiki. Imagine that the energy goes to Glandula Pineal and that fills you with harmony and happiness.</string>
    <string name="cinco_princ_pios_s_o_a_nossa_base_o_in_cio_e_o_fim_da_pr_tica_como_dizia_o_mestre_usui_pratica_os_sentindo_os_princ_pios_a_ressoar_em_todo_o_teu_corpo_n_n_nespero_que_tenhas_gostado_destes_sete_dias_de_caminho_que_fomos_percorrendo_ao_longo_dos_princ_pios_e_dos_chacras_fico_te_grato_pela_companhia_nesta_bonita_jornada_de_autocrescimento">* Five Principles - they are our base, the beginning and the end of the practice, as Master Usui said. Practice them by feeling the principles resonate throughout your body.\n\n\nI hope you enjoyed these seven days of the journey, which we went through along the principles and chakras. I am grateful for the company on this beautiful journey of self-growth.</string>
    <string name="obrigadopeladoacao">\n\nThanks for your donation :D</string>
    <string name="doar">Donate</string>
    <string name="gassho">GASSHO</string>
    <string name="reiji_ho">Reiji-Ho</string>
    <string name="chiryo">CHIRYO</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="informa_ao">Info</string>
    <string name="tecnicagasshoexplicacao">\nThe Gassho technique means your folded hands, ”or together, and consists of concentrating your empty mind and feeling the flow of Reiki energy.</string>
    <string name="chiryoexplicacao">Chiryo is "treatment", the very practice of treatment and which, according to Master Usui\'s guidelines, you must practice after Gassho and Reiji-Ho.</string>
    <string name="reiji_ho_explicacao">Reiji-Ho means a method of indicating Reiki energy », Feel the energy flowing into your body and feel the blockages you may have. Or you can do the same for someone else\'s body. This technique is the feeling of the flow of energy.</string>
    <string name="dia_1_0_observar">DAY 1 - OBSERVE</string>
    <string name="dia_2_a_mente">DAY 2 - THE MIND</string>
    <string name="dia_3_desintoxicar_libertar">DAY 3 - DETOX = RELEASE</string>
    <string name="dia_4_plena_aten_o_na_pr_tica">DAY 4 - FULL ATTENTION IN PRACTICE</string>
    <string name="dia_5_aviv_ncia_no_aqui_e_agora">DAY 5 - EXPERIENCE IN HERE AND NOW</string>
    <string name="as_chamas_ardentes_da_raiva_secaram_o_rio_do_meu_ser_a_densa_obscuridade_da_ilus_o_cegou_a_minha_intelig_ncia_a_minha_consci_ncia_afoga_se_nas_torrentes_do_desejo_a_nevasca_enregelada_da_inveja_arrastou_me_para_o_samsara_a_montanha_do_orgulho_precipitou_me_nos_mundos_inferiores_o_dem_nio_da_cren_a_no_ego_tem_me_firme_pela_garganta_dilgo_khyentse_rimpoche_n_nneste_conjunto_de_cinco_dias_vamos_trabalhar_o_reiki_na_perspetiva_da_aten_o_plena_a_pr_tica_do_reiki_incrivelmente_completa_resumi_la_apenas_terapia_extremamente_redutor_meditar_com_o_reiki_uma_experi_ncia_transformadora_e_isso_que_quero_partilhar_contigo_ao_longo_destes_cinco_dias_vai_fazendo_os_exerc_cios_dentro_do_teu_tempo_sente_e_observa_as_tuas_pr_prias_evolu_o_e_mudan_a">«The burning flames of anger dried up the river of my being, The dense darkness of the illusion blinded my intelligence. My conscience drowns in the floods of desire. The freezing blizzard of envy dragged me into samsara. The mountain of pride precipitated me into the lower worlds. The demon of belief in the ego has me, firmly, by the throat. » - Dilgo Khyentse Rimpoche\n\nIn this set of five days we will work with Reiki from the perspective of mindfulness. The practice of Reiki is incredibly complete, to summarize it only to therapy is extremely reducing. Meditating with Reiki is a transformative experience and that is what I want to share with you over these five days. Do the exercises within your time, feel and observe your own evolution and change.</string>
    <string name="observar">OBSERVE</string>
    <string name="as_mem_rias_assaltam_nos_o_julgamento_prende_e_oprime_nos_assim_deixamos_de_querer_ter_consci_ncia_e_de_olhar_para_dentro_quere_mos_apenas_fazer_e_n_o_ser_como_ultrapassar_ent_o_a_dor_da_mem_ria_o_peso_da_a_o_praticada_e_o_julgamento_n_n_a_vida_tem_um_prop_sito_definido_ter_a_pr_pria_escurid_o_da_mente_dissipada_e_assim_alcan_ar_a_felicidade_sem_fim_kentetsu_takamori_n_nobservar_n_o_implica_apegar_quando_observamos_o_interior_e_nos_percorrem_todas_aquelas_emo_es_pesadas_fruto_das_mem_rias_que_fomos_recalcando_sentimos_a_tristeza_o_sofrimento_a_dor_fisica_somatizada_algo_que_apenas_uma_mem_ria_foi_aconteceu_passado_na_observa_o_em_consci_ncia_estamos_neutros_entregamo_nos_ao_ato_de_compaix_o_que_permite_sanar_a_dor_e_iluminar_a_escurid_o_da_mente_na_compreens_o_n_o_h_apego_no_amor_incondicional_e_na_compaix_o_n_o_h_apego_olhar_para_dentro_ter_o_maior_ato_de_compaix_o_em_todo_o_universo_dar_valor_vida_que_temos_criando_espa_o_para_a_felicidade_se_desenvolver_e_permanecer_em_n_s_inspirar_expirar_de_consci_ncia_centrada_tenta_olhar_para_dentro_sem_sofrimento_compreendendo_o_caminho_que_leva_para_fora_dele">Memories assail us, judgment arrests and oppresses us. So we stop wanting to be aware and look inside, we just want to do and not be. How to overcome the pain of memory, the weight of the action and judgment?\n\n«Life has a definite purpose: to have the very darkness of the mind dissipated, and thus achieve endless happiness.» - Kentetsu Takamori\n\nObserving does not imply attachment. When we look inside and all those heavy emotions run through us, as a result of the memories that we have been repressing, we feel sadness, suffering, physical pain plus something that is just a memory. Was. It happened. Past. In observation, in consciousness, we are neutral. We surrender to the act of compassion that allows us to heal pain and illuminate the darkness of the mind. In understanding there is no attachment, in unconditional love and compassion there is no attachment. To look inside is to have the greatest act of compassion in the entire Universe - It is to give value to the life we ​​have, creating space for happiness to develop and remain in us. It is inhaling, exhaling, centered awareness. Try to look inside without suffering, understanding the path that leads out of it.</string>
    <string name="exerc_cios">EXERCISES</string>
    <string name="para_este_primeiro_dia_desenvolve_a_tua_capacidade_de_observa_o_come_a_qualquer_atividade_de_reiki_com_o_esvaziar_da_mente_n_n1_visualiza_uma_sala_no_interior_da_tua_mente_como_est_n2_esvazia_a_sala_e_pinta_as_paredes_o_teto_e_o_ch_o_de_branco_n_nrepete_este_exerc_cio_v_rias_vezes_ao_longo_do_tempo_e_no_intervalo_dos_exerc_cios_e_importante_desenvolveres_o_conceito_de_mente_limpa_e_de_estar_no_aqui_e_agora_mesmo_no_desenvolvimento_da_intui_o_importante_uma_mente_vazia_onde_as_situa_es_possam_surgir_e_revelar_se_n_ncoloca_a_tua_aten_o_na_forma_como_te_ligas_ao_reiki_n_n1_sente_o_contacto_das_tuas_m_os_n2_sente_como_a_energia_te_toca_n3_sente_o_seu_fluir_no_teu_interior_n_ncomo_flui_a_energia_no_teu_cora_o_como_seria_se_lhe_desses_cor_e_forma_npratica_o_joshin_kokyu_ho_al_m_de_te_desenvolver_a_energia_vital_centra_te_neste_fluxo_de_ar_que_entra_e_que_sai_n_o_pensando_em_mais_nada_parecem_exerc_cios_muito_simples_mas_n_o_s_o_se_os_dominares_ent_o_conseguiste_alcan_ar_uma_plena_consci_ncia_de_ti">For this first day, develop your observation skills. Any Reiki activity begins with the emptying of the mind:\n\n1- Visualize a room inside your mind, how is it?\n2- Empty the room and paint the walls, ceiling and floor white.\n\nRepeat this exercise several times over time and in between the exercises. It is important to develop the concept of a clear mind and being in the here and now. Even in the development of intuition, it is important to have an empty mind where situations can arise and reveal themselves.\n\nPut your attention on how you connect to Reiki.\n\n1- Feel the contact of your hands;\n2- Feel how the energy touches you;\n3- Feel its flow inside you.\n\nHow does the energy flow in your heart? What would it be like if you gave it color and shape?\nPractice Joshin Kokyu Ho, in addition to developing your vital energy, focus on this flow of air in and out, thinking of nothing else. They look like very simple exercises but they are not. If you master them, then you have achieved full awareness of yourself.</string>
    <string name="primeiro_temos_de_cultivar_a_aten_o_plena_para_manifestarmos_e_emanarmos_reiki_devemos_focar_e_purificar_a_mente_kenji_hamamoto_n_ndepois_da_atitude_de_observa_o_e_de_te_conheceres_como_observador_vamos_aprofundar_a_mente">«First we have to cultivate mindfulness. To manifest and emanate Reiki we must focus and purify the mind. » - Kenji Hamamoto\n\nAfter the attitude of observation and knowing yourself as an observer, we will deepen the mind.</string>
    <string name="a_mente">THE MIND</string>
    <string name="a_mente_dificil_de_ser_controlada_sempre_veloz_inclina_se_perante_aquilo_que_deseja_e_bom_o_treino_da_mente_uma_mente_bem_domada_traz_felicidade_buda_n_na_mente_n_o_um_parasita_nem_algo_estranho_a_n_s_e_uma_parte_nossa_uma_cria_o_natural_nossa_e_deve_ser_abordada_com_a_mesma_compaix_o_com_que_abordamos_uma_ferida_e_com_a_mesma_import_ncia_e_o_respeito_com_que_encaramos_o_esp_rito_ou_os_nossos_ideais_a_mente_produz_cria_e_ajuda_nos_a_ter_uma_perce_o_da_realidade_umas_vezes_concreta_outras_vezes_deturpada_e_ent_o_nossa_responsabilidade_a_do_observador_saber_instruir_a_mente_para_que_possa_trabalhar_de_forma_s_ncrona_com_o_cora_o_para_nos_trazer_a_vis_o_correta_do_mundo_se_tens_uma_mente_demasiadamente_produtiva_n_o_te_entregues_nem_te_abandones_a_ela_antes_pelo_contr_rio_adquire_dom_nio_sobre_ela_educa_a_e_d_lhe_compaix_o_e_amor_reiki_j_pensaste_em_enviar_reiki_para_a_tua_mente">«The mind is difficult to control: it is always fast, it leans towards what it wants. The training of the mind is good; a well-tamed mind brings happiness. » -Buddha\n\nThe mind is not a parasite or anything foreign to us. It is a part of us, a natural creation of ours and must be approached with the same compassion with which we approach a wound and with the same importance and the respect with which we face the spirit or our ideals. The mind produces, creates and helps us to have a perception of reality - sometimes concrete, sometimes distorted. And then our responsibility, that of the observer, to know how to instruct the mind so that it can work synchronously with the heart to bring us the correct view of the world. If you have an overly productive mind, do not surrender or abandon yourself to it, on the contrary: acquire mastery over it, educate it and give it compassion and love - Reiki. Have you thought about sending Reiki to your mind?</string>
    <string name="como_correram_os_exerc_cios_de_ontem_se_quiseres_mant_m_a_mesma_pr_tica_principalmente_esvaziar_a_mente_essa_mesmo_muito_importante_os_exerc_cios_de_hoje_v_o_centrar_se_nas_tuas_atividades_com_o_reiki_ser_a_que_deves_aplicar_toda_a_tua_aten_o_n_n1_ao_fazeres_a_liga_o_com_o_reiki_coloca_te_apenas_no_momento_presente_sente_como_est_s_sente_o_percurso_da_energia_a_entrar_em_ti_n2_nos_cinco_princ_pios_deixa_cada_um_ressoar_em_ti_entrega_a_tua_energia_e_o_reiki_a_cada_um_dos_princ_pios_e_observa_como_te_transformam_n3_no_autotratamento_mant_m_a_mente_vazia_e_apenas_sente_percebe_como_est_essa_parte_do_corpo_sente_o_que_a_energia_te_aporta_antes_de_mudares_de_posi_o_sente_como_est_s_n4_no_tratamento_aos_outros_deixa_a_energia_fluir_com_a_tua_aten_o_apenas_no_fluxo_constante_n_o_te_prendas_ao_que_sentes_quanto_outra_pessoa_ganha_o_dom_nio_da_tua_mente_e_das_emo_es_e_mant_m_te_centrado_entrega_te_respira_o_ao_enraizamento_uma_coisa_de_cada_vez_deixando_fluir_n_ncomo_te_sentes_n_nnotas_alguma_diferen_a_quando_exerces_uma_total_aten_o_no_que_est_s_a_fazer">How did yesterday\'s exercises go? If you want to keep the same practice, especially emptying your mind - this is really important. Today\'s exercises will focus on your Reiki activities - this is where you should apply all your attention:\n\n1- When you make the connection with Reiki, put yourself only in the present moment - feel how you are, feel the path of energy entering you;\n2- In the Five Principles, let each one resonate with you. Give your energy and Reiki to each of the principles and observe how they transform you;\n3- In self-treatment, keep your mind empty and just feel - notice how that part of the body is, feel what the energy brings you. Before you change your position, feel how you are;\n4- In treating others let the energy flow with your attention only in the constant flow. Don\'t get attached to what you feel about the other person, gain control of your mind and emotions and stay centered. Give yourself to the breath, to the rooting, one thing at a time, letting it flow.\n\nHow do you feel?\n\nDo you notice any difference when you pay full attention to what you are doing?</string>
    <string name="nada_te_posso_dar_a_n_o_ser_a_oportunidade_o_impulso_a_chave_eu_ajudarei_a_tornar_vis_vel_o_teu_pr_prio_mundo_e_isso_tudo_hermann_hesse_n_nhoje_vamos_concentrar_a_aten_o_na_nossa_desintoxica_o_quando_recitamos_os_cinco_princ_pios_estamos_a_desintoxicar_a_mente_e_o_cora_o_quando_fazemos_o_autotratamento_estamos_a_desintoxicar_todos_os_nossos_corpos_hoje_exatamente_isso_que_faremos_com_cinco_prinapios_e_autotratamento_vamos_trabalhar_a_nossa_desintoxica_o_encara_estes_exerc_cios_com_alegria_e_deixa_fluir_o_reiki">«I can give you nothing but the opportunity, the momentum, the key. I will help to make your own world visible, and that is all. » - Hermann Hesse\n\nToday we are going to focus attention on our detox. When we recite the Five Principles we are detoxifying the mind and heart, when we do self-treatment we are detoxifying all our bodies. Today is exactly what we will do - with Five Prinapios and self-treatment, we will work on our detoxification. Face these exercises with joy and let Reiki flow.</string>
    <string name="a_desintoxica_o_pode_ser_feita_de_v_rias_formas_fisica_mental_emocional_energ_tica_e_at_espiritual_tenta_perceber_de_que_forma_te_sentes_mais_intoxicado_ou_bloqueado_n_n_f_sico_n_mental_n_emocional_n_energ_tico_n_espiritual_n_nno_teu_corpo_fisico_experimenta_avaliar_a_tua_alimenta_o_dedica_te_a_caminhar_mais_a_fazer_o_cora_o_funcionar_para_cada_um_dos_outros_corpos_incluindo_tamb_m_o_fisico_vamos_aplicar_hoje_duas_t_cnica_gedoku_chiryo_ho_e_a_medita_o_gassho_no_cap_tulo_de_t_cnicas_podemos_encontrar_a_respetiva_descri_o_n_n_primeiro_faz_o_teu_autotratamento_como_costumas_fazer_e_depois_do_chacra_do_plexo_solar_n_coloca_a_m_o_esquerda_em_cima_do_tanden_dois_dedos_abaixo_de_umbigo_e_em_seguida_p_e_a_direita_exatamente_na_mesma_direc_o_mas_nas_costas_n_visualiza_todas_as_toxinas_fisicas_mentais_emocionais_energ_ticas_espirituais_a_sa_rem_de_ti_n_n_o_te_preocupes_se_saem_pela_barriga_ou_pelos_p_s_deixa_as_apenas_sair_n_naqui_ao_fazeres_o_gedoku_tamb_m_podes_praticar_a_aten_o_plena_isto_quer_dizer_que_deves_apenas_concentrar_te_no_fluxo_de_reiki_que_entra_e_de_energia_densa_que_sai_sem_te_focares_nos_aspetos_negativos_nisto_muito_til_porque_assim_aprender_s_a_dar_import_ncia_ao_que_mais_importante_se_v_s_que_n_o_consegues_faz_a_seguinte_pergunta_a_ti_mesmo_e_mais_importante_focares_te_na_cura_ou_na_doen_a_termina_o_teu_autotratamento_faz_o_banho_seco_e_a_chuva_de_reiki_n_npassa_medita_o_n_nsenta_te_confortavelmente_presta_aten_o_tua_postura_e_endireita_te_para_que_o_canal_flua_serenamente_primeiro_foca_te_na_mente_n_n_visualiza_o_interior_da_cabe_a_como_sendo_uma_sala_n_esvazia_a_sala_por_completo_n_pinta_as_paredes_de_branco_assim_como_o_ch_o_e_o_teto_n_verifica_se_tudo_est_vazio_n_permanece_nesse_vazio_n_nexecuta_a_gassho_n_n1_senta_te_confortavelmente_com_os_p_s_bem_assentes_no_ch_o_para_que_a_energia_flua_os_ombros_relaxados_as_costas_direitas_o_queixo_ligeiramente_inclinado_para_baixo_n2_coloca_as_m_os_em_posi_o_gassho_m_os_juntas_encostadas_ao_chacra_card_aco_n3_leva_a_aten_o_para_o_ponto_onde_os_dois_dedos_m_dios_se_encontram_e_sente_a_energia_que_se_concentra_nessa_regi_o_n4_mant_m_te_no_aqui_e_agora_e_respira_suavemente_fazendo_uma_respira_o_completa_leva_a_energia_ao_tanden_n5_mant_m_te_focado_na_energia_que_entra_pelos_teus_dedos_e_vai_para_o_tanden_e_ao_expirar_na_energia_que_vai_do_tanden_at_aos_dedos_saindo_para_o_exterior_n_o_te_deixes_ir_atr_s_dos_pensamentos_apenas_constata_mas_mant_m_te_centrado_n6_quando_sentires_que_est_s_pronto_inspira_muito_reiki_e_recita_os_cinco_princ_pios_centrado_no_cora_o_fazendo_os_vibrar_do_interior_para_o_exterior_pausadamente_n_ns_por_hoje_sou_calmo_confio_sou_grato_trabalho_honestamente_e_sou_bondoso_n_n7_permanece_no_vazio_da_tua_mente_apenas_preenchido_pela_vibra_o_dos_cinco_princ_pios_e_sente_como_est_s_imagina_a_vibra_o_a_fluir_para_a_tua_aura_para_todo_o_espa_o_que_te_rodeia_n8_quando_quiseres_abre_os_olhos_e_traz_essa_vibra_o_para_o_teu_dia">Detoxification can be done in various ways - physical, mental, emotional, energetic and even spiritual. Try to understand how you feel more intoxicated or blocked:\n\n- Physic?\n- Mental?\n- Emotional?\n- Energetic?\n- Spiritual?\n\nIn your physical body, try to evaluate your diet. Dedicate yourself to walking more, making your heart work. For each of the other bodies (including also the physical one) we will apply two techniques today Gedoku Chiryo Ho and Gassho meditation. In the chapter of techniques we can find the respective description.\n\n* First do your self-treatment as you usually do and then the Solar Plexus Chakra;\n* Place your left hand on top of the Tanden (two fingers below your navel) and then put your right in exactly the same direction but on your back;\n* Visualize all toxins (physical, mental, emotional, energetic, spiritual) coming out of you;\n* Don\'t worry if they leave by the belly or by the feet, just let them out.\n\nHere, when doing Gedoku you can also practice mindfulness - this means that you should just concentrate on the flow of Reiki that comes in and the dense energy that comes out, without focusing on the negative aspects.\nThis is very useful, because then you will learn to give importance to what is most important. If you see that you can\'t, ask yourself the following question: Is it more important to focus on healing or disease? Finish your self-treatment, do the dry bath and the Reiki rain.\n\nGo to meditation:\n\nSit comfortably, pay attention to your posture and straighten up, so that the channel flows smoothly. First focus on the mind:\n\n* Visualizes the interior of the head as a room;\n* Empty the room completely;\n* Paint the walls white, as well as the floor and ceiling;\n* Checks if everything is empty;\n* It remains in that void.\n\nGassho runs:\n\n1- Sit comfortably, with your feet firmly on the floor so that the energy flows, your shoulders relaxed, your back straight, your chin slightly tilted down;\n2- Put your hands in the Gassho position (hands together) leaning against the Heart Chakra;\n3- Take your attention to the point where the two middle fingers meet and feel the energy that is concentrated in that region;\n4- Stay in the here and now and breathe gently, taking a full breath. It takes energy to Tanden;\n5- Stay focused on the energy that enters your fingers and goes to Tanden and, on expiration, the energy that goes from Tanden to your fingers, leaving for the outside. Do not let yourself go after the thoughts, just note but stay centered;\n6- When you feel that you are ready, inspire a lot of Reiki and recite the Five Principles, centered in the heart, making them vibrate from the inside to the outside, slowly;\n\nJust for today, I am calm, I trust, I am grateful, I work honestly and I am kind.\n\n7- Remain in the void of your mind, just filled with the vibration of the Five Principles, and feel how you are. Imagine the vibration flowing into your aura, into the entire space around you;\n8- Whenever you want, open your eyes and bring that vibration to your day.</string>
    <string name="uma_jornada_de_mil_milhas_come_a_com_um_simples_passo_lao_tsu_n_nespero_que_estejas_a_gostar_destes_momentos_para_o_desenvolvimento_da_plena_aten_o_com_o_reiki_hoje_vamos_focar_nos_na_pr_tica_no_fluxo_da_energia">«A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step.» - Lao-Tsu\n\nI hope you are enjoying these moments for the development of mindfulness, with Reiki. Today we are going to focus on practice, on the flow of energy.</string>
    <string name="hoje_vamos_levar_a_aten_o_plena_ao_fluxo_da_energia_e_aos_s_mbolos_a_pr_tica_muito_simples_e_podes_faz_la_ap_s_o_teu_autotratamento_ou_quando_sentires_que_tens_disposi_o_para_tal_n_o_te_esque_as_de_preparar_o_momento_e_de_sentires_te_confort_vel_n_npara_quem_tem_n_vel_1_de_reiki_n_nliga_te_energia_e_quando_sentires_o_fluxo_de_reiki_chegar_s_m_os_faz_o_seguinte_n_n1_fecha_os_olhos_e_limpa_a_mente_n2_concentra_te_no_chacra_da_palma_das_m_os_n3_sente_o_que_se_passa_nessa_zona_n4_como_flui_a_energia_at_ao_chacra_n5_como_sai_a_energia_do_chacra_n6_se_o_chacra_tivesse_uma_cor_qual_seria_n7_acompanha_o_percurso_da_energia_a_sair_das_tuas_m_os_como_sentes_a_energia_bom_n_nesta_t_cnica_ir_ajudar_te_a_focar_e_perceber_o_que_est_s_a_fazer_com_o_envio_de_reiki_um_desenvolvimento_incr_vel_da_consci_ncia_experimenta_v_rias_vezes_pois_ser_sempre_diferente_n_npara_quem_tem_o_n_vel_2_ou_3_n_npodes_usar_o_s_mbolo_com_que_te_sentires_mais_confort_vel_o_ideal_ser_experimentar_todos_os_s_mbolos_se_sentires_algum_mal_estar_emocional_ou_energ_tico_alivia_a_press_o_do_s_mbolo_afastando_o_inspira_reiki_e_ao_expirar_deixa_sair_o_que_n_o_queres_se_esta_situa_o_aconteceu_bom_sinal_de_que_precisavas_de_ser_tratado_com_o_s_mbolo_n_n1_sente_como_a_energia_flui_para_o_cora_o_e_de_l_para_todo_o_corpo_n2_deixa_a_energia_reiki_sair_pelas_m_os_e_pelos_p_s_e_sente_como_se_todo_o_interior_fosse_lavado_por_essa_energia_n3_concentra_te_no_s_mbolo_que_escolheste_n4_desenha_o_s_mbolo_frente_do_tamanho_do_corpo_se_visualzares_cores_podes_v_lo_dourado_violeta_verde_ou_azul_n5_diz_o_seu_mantra_tr_s_vezes_para_o_ativar_n6_sente_a_sua_vibra_o_como_o_simbolo_vibra_em_contacto_com_a_tua_aura_n7_tr_lo_lentamente_para_mais_perto_do_teu_corpo_sempre_sentindo_a_sua_vibra_o_n8_verifica_se_transmite_alguma_imagem_ou_impress_o_na_terceira_vis_o_n9_saboreia_o_momento_n10_quando_quiseres_imagina_o_s_mbolo_a_dissolver_se_na_tua_aura_preenchendo_a_com_as_suas_vibra_o_e_energia_n11_usufrui_essa_vibra_o_durante_algum_tempo_n12_quando_quiseres_terminar_n_o_te_esque_as_de_enraizar_tomar_consci_ncia_do_corpo_e_do_aqui_e_agora_n13_toma_nota_do_que_se_passou_na_medita_o_e_se_tiveres_alguma_sugest_o_de_algo_a_tratar_ou_a_fazer_faz_esse_tratamento_que_a_intui_o_te_pede_n_nquando_o_reiki_flui_mesmo_um_momento_especial_e_maravilhoso_somos_muito_afortunados_por_podermos_e_sabermos_praticar_s_por_isso_vale_a_pena_dizer_s_por_hoje_sou_grato_sou_grato_tamb_m_a_ti_por_este_caminho_e_pela_companhia_nestes_cinco_dias">Today we are going to take full attention to the flow of energy and symbols. The practice is very simple and you can do it after your self-treatment or when you feel that you are willing to do so. Don\'t forget to prepare for the moment and feel comfortable.\n\nFor those who have Reiki Level 1\n\nConnect with the energy and, when you feel the flow of Reiki reaching your hands, do the following:\n\n1- Close your eyes and clear your mind;\n2- Focus on the palm chakra;\n3- Feel what is happening in that area;\n4- How energy flows to the chakra;\n5- How the chakra energy comes out;\n6- If the chakra had a color, which would it be?\n7- Follow the path of energy coming out of your hands. How do you feel the energy? It\'s good?\n\nThis technique will help you to focus and understand what you are doing with sending Reiki. It is an incredible development of consciousness. Try it several times, as it will always be different.\n\nFor those who have Level 2 or 3\n\nYou can use the symbol you are most comfortable with. The ideal is to try all the symbols. If you feel any emotional or energetic discomfort, relieve the pressure of the symbol, pushing it away. Inhale Reiki and, as you exhale, let out what you don\'t want. If this situation is good, it is a sign that you needed to be treated with the symbol.\n\n1- Feel how the energy flows to the heart and from there to the whole body;\n2- Let the Reiki energy come out through the hands and feet and feel as if the entire interior was washed by this energy;\n3- Focus on the symbol you have chosen;\n4- Draw the symbol at the front, the size of the body (if you see colors, you can see it gold, violet, green or blue);\n5- Say your mantra three times to activate it;\n6- Feel your vibration, as the symbol vibrates in contact with your aura;\n7- Bring it slowly closer to your body, always feeling its vibration;\n8- Checks if it transmits any image or impression in the Third Vision;\n9- Savor the moment;\n10- Whenever you want, imagine the symbol dissolving in your aura, filling it with its vibration and energy;\n11- Enjoy this vibration for some time;\n12- When you want to finish don\'t forget to take root, become aware of the body and the here and now;\n13- Take note of what happened in meditation and, if you have any suggestions for something to do or do, do this treatment that your intuition asks for.\n\nWhen Reiki flows it is really a special and wonderful time. We are very fortunate to be able and know how to practice. For that alone, it is worth saying "Just for today, I am grateful". I am also grateful to you, for this path and for the company in these five days.</string>
    <string name="a_miss_o_do_usui_reiki_ryoho_guiar_para_uma_vida_pac_fica_e_feliz_curar_os_outros_melhorar_a_sua_felicidade_e_a_nossa_mikao_usui_n_ncomo_foram_para_ti_estes_cinco_dias_n_nespero_que_tenhas_tido_boas_experi_ncias_hoje_vamos_ver_como_trazer_tudo_o_que_fizemos_e_um_bocadinho_mais_para_uma_viv_ncia_no_aqui_e_agora">«Usui Reiki Ryoho\'s mission is to guide you towards a peaceful and happy life, to heal others, to improve your happiness and ours.» - Mikao Usui\n\nHow were these five days for you?\n\nI hope you have had good experiences. Today we are going to see how to bring everything we did, and a little more, to an experience in the here and now.</string>
    <string name="quando_aprendemos_a_ler_praticamos_praticamos_e_praticamos_levamos_anos_a_desenvolver_uma_leitura_correta_uma_dic_o_correta_e_chegamos_a_um_momento_em_que_nos_esquecemos_de_como_foi_dificil_essa_aprendizagem_ndesenvolver_a_aten_o_plena_requer_os_mesmos_esp_rito_e_vis_o_demora_tempo_muito_tempo_requer_pr_tica_pr_tica_e_pr_tica_e_quando_l_chegamos_parece_que_foi_simples_pois_est_integrado_com_a_integra_o_que_conseguimos_mais_rapidamente_atingir_um_bom_resultado_se_aplicarmos_a_nossa_aten_o_nas_pequenas_coisas_do_dia_a_dia_mais_depressa_aprendemos_a_controlar_a_mente_e_a_viver_de_forma_mais_equilibrada_descobrindo_como_reconhecer_pensamentos_e_emo_es_sabendo_como_os_gerir_nneste_dia_vamos_fazer_coisas_simples_para_desenvolver_a_plena_aten_o_no_dia_a_dia_n_n_quando_beberes_o_teu_caf_ou_ch_saboreia_aproveita_cada_gole_que_d_s_diferente_o_que_sentes_n_quando_falares_com_algu_m_foca_te_apenas_na_conversa_e_n_o_fa_as_duas_coisas_ao_mesmo_tempo_como_correu_n_no_teu_trabalho_experimenta_ao_responder_a_um_e_mail_fechar_tudo_o_resto_e_focares_te_apenas_naquela_resposta_como_foi_n_quando_o_telem_vel_tocar_n_o_atendas_logo_deixa_tocar_tr_s_vezes_e_pensa_que_as_minhas_palavras_sejam_bondosas_como_correu_n_nal_m_destas_tarefas_podes_adicionar_outras_mas_coloca_tamb_m_algo_muito_importante_n_n_ao_longo_do_dia_recita_v_rias_vezes_os_cinco_princ_pios_com_plena_aten_o_pausadamente_fazendo_vibrar_em_ti_cada_palavra_cada_sentimento_ser_que_esta_pr_tica_ir_mudar_o_teu_dia_n_no_quinto_dia_um_reflexo_de_tudo_o_que_j_praticaste_mesmo_a_leitura_destas_p_ginas_pode_ser_feita_com_toda_a_aten_o_poss_vel_n_ndesejo_que_estes_cinco_dias_tenham_sido_muito_bonitos_para_ti_e_que_principalmente_te_tenham_levado_a_momentos_de_paz_o_reiki_pede_nos_uma_pr_tica_constante_que_serve_para_nos_construir_enquanto_pessoas_melhores_e_mais_felizes_temos_de_confiar_e_ser_bondosos_connosco">When we learn to read, we practice, practice and practice. It took us years to develop a correct reading, a correct diction, and we came to a time when we forgot how difficult that learning was.\nDeveloping mindfulness requires the same spirit and vision - it takes time, a lot of time, it takes practice, practice and practice, and when we get there it seems that it was simple because it is integrated. It is with the integration that we can more quickly achieve a good result. If we apply our attention to the little things of everyday life, the sooner we learn to control the mind and live more evenly, discovering how to recognize thoughts and emotions, knowing how to manage them.\nOn this day we will do simple things, to develop mindfulness on a daily basis:\n\n* When you sip your coffee or tea, enjoy every sip you take. Is it different how you feel?\n* When talking to someone, just focus on the conversation and don\'t do two things at the same time. How did it go?\n* In your work, try, when replying to an email, close everything else and focus only on that answer. How was it?\n* When the phone rings, don\'t answer it right away. Let it ring three times and think "my words are kind". How did it go?\n\nIn addition to these tasks, you can add others. But, it also puts something very important:\n\n* Throughout the day, recite the Five Principles several times with full attention, slowly, making every word, every feeling vibrate in you. Will this practice change your day?\n\nThe fifth day is a reflection of everything you\'ve done. Even reading these pages can be done with as much attention as possible.\n\nI hope that these five days have been very beautiful for you and that, above all, have taken you to moments of peace. Reiki asks us for constant practice, which serves to build us as better and happier people. We have to trust and be kind to us.</string>

</resources>
